There are a couple of notes I wanted to mention about object-oriented programming.
关于面向对象编程 我想提几点注意事项
In the first part of the lesson,
在这节课的第一部分
you'll be doing coding exercises in Jupiter Notebooks.
你将在 Jupyter Notebook 中完成编程练习
When writing software however,
但是在编写软件时
you generally wouldn't write object-oriented programs in a Jupiter Notebook.
通常不会在 Jupyter Notebook 中编写面向对象程序
Instead, you would modularize the code into separate Python scripts.
而是将代码分成独立的 Python 脚本
In the the second half of the lesson,
在这节课的第二部分
you'll be modularizing code.
你将使代码模块化
So here, I'm going to give a preview of what's to come later in the lesson.
现在我将大致介绍接下来将用到的工具
If you haven't seen this particular interface and other Udacity courses or lessons,
如果你没有在其他优达学城课程中见过这个界面的话
this is called a workspace.
我来介绍下 它叫做 workspace
It's imbedded in the classroom and you'll use it later in the lesson.
它内嵌在了教室中 稍后你将用到它
This is a Linux Ubuntu environment where you can write and execute Python code.
这是一个 Linux Ubuntu 环境 你可以在该环境里编写和执行 Python 代码
In one file, I've put the shirt class code and called the file shirt.py.
我将 Shirt 类代码放在了其中一个文件里 并将该文件命名为 shirt.py
Now, I'm going to write a separate Python script that uses the shirt class code.
现在我将编写另一个 Python 脚本 其中会使用 Shirt 类的代码
In the same folder,
我在同一个文件夹里
I've created another file called example.py.
创建了另一个叫做 example.py 的文件
Inside example.py, I want to use the shirt class.
我想在 example.py 文件里使用 Shirt 类
First, I need to import the shirt class typing from shirt import shirt.
首先 我需要导入 Shirt 类 输入 from shirt import Shirt
The lowercase shirt refers to the shirt.py file.
小写的 shirt 是指 shirt.py 文件
The uppercase shirt refers to the class defined inside this file.
首字母大写的 Shirt 是指在此文件里定义的类
I could name the file and class anything I wanted to.
我可以将该文件和类命名为任何名称
They don't have to be the same.
它们不是必须要采用相同的名称
I just did this for convenience.
我这么命名只是为了方便
Now, in example.py, I can use
现在我可以像在之前的练习中一样
the shirt class just like what you did in the previous exercise.
在 example.py 中使用 Shirt 类
The difference is that the code is now modularized.
区别只是现在的代码已经模块化
I'll write some code that uses the shirt class.
我将编写一些利用 Shirt 类的代码
Finally, I'm going to run the code in the terminal.
最后 我将在终端里运行代码
First, I'm going to change the directory I'm in to
首先 我将更改我所在的目录
make sure I'm in the directory with the Python files,
确保我位于包含这些 Python 文件的目录中
and then I'm going to type Python example.py.
然后输入 python example.py
Okay. So, the output or the print statements I had in the code.
输出结果是在代码里已设定的输出语句
On a separate topic,
接下来
I wanted to mention how to access attribute values and change attribute values in Python.
我将介绍如何在 Python 中访问和更改属性值
The shirt class has a method to change the price of the shirt.
Shirt 类具有一个更改衬衫价格的方法
You can see in line nine in example.py, shirt_two.changeprice 45.
例如 example.py 文件第 9 行的代码 shirt_two.change_price(45)
In Python, you can also change the values of an attribute with the following syntax,
在 Python 里还可以使用以下语法更改属性值
shirt_one.color equals red, shirt_one.size equals large.
shirt_one.color = 'red'  shirt_one.size = 'L'
Let me go back. Shirt one is already red so let's say yellow
抱歉 重新修改下 shirt_one 已经是红色 因此改成黄色
and shirt_one.price equals 43.
并且 shirt_one.price = 43
There are some drawbacks to accessing attributes directly
与使用方法访问和显示属性相比
versus writing a method for accessing and displaying attributes.
直接访问属性存在不足之处
In terms of object oriented programming,
对于面向对象编程来说
the rules in Python are a bit looser than in other programming languages.
Python 跟其他编程语言有点不同
In some languages like C++,
例如 在 C++ 等语言中
you can explicitly state whether or not an object should be
你可以设置不允许
allowed to change or access an attribute values directly.
直接更改或访问某个对象的属性
Python does not have this option.
Python 就没有这类设置 它允许直接访问/获取属性
Why might it be better to change a value with
为何通过方法更改值
a method instead of changing a value directly?
比直接更改值更好？
Changing values via a method gives you more flexibility in the long-term.
从长远来看 通过方法更改值使代码更灵活
But if the units of measurement changed like the store was
比如 如果计量单位变了 该怎么办？
originally meant to work in US dollars and now has to work in euros.
假设商店一开始采用的是美元 现在需要采用欧元
Here's what I mean, if you've changed an attribute directly like in line 14,
假设你直接更改第 14 行的属性
if all of a sudden I have to use euros,
现在忽然需要使用欧元
I'm going to have to manually change this to say 38.
我只能手动修改 例如改成 38 欧元
You're going to have to do this wherever you access the price attribute directly.
所有直接访问价格属性的地方 都需要这样的手动修改
If on the other hand you would use a method like the change price method,
但是如果使用方法的话 例如 change_price 方法
then all you have to do is go into
那么只需转到 Shirt 类
the shirt class and change the original method one time.
更改原始方法 并且更改一次就够了
I'm just going to multiply by 0.81 to convert everything from dollars to euros.
我只需乘以 0.81 就能将所有价格从美元换算成欧元
Now, if you go back to example.py,
现在回到 example.py
a line like number 9,
对于第 9 行来说
you don't have to manually change the price from dollars to euros
不需要手动地将价格从美元改成欧元
because the conversion is going to take care of that for you in the shirt class.
因为 Shirt 类会自动进行换算
For the purposes of this introduction to object-oriented programming,
对于这门面向对象编程入门课程来说
you will not need to worry about updating attributes directly versus using a method.
你不需要思考是直接更新属性还是使用方法更新
However, if you decide to further your studies of object oriented programming,
但是 如果你决定深入学习面向对象编程
especially in another language such as C++ or Java,
尤其是 C++ 或 Java 等其他语言
you'll have to take this into consideration.
则需要考虑这方面的因素